¬text for event images

¬ =============================================================================================
¬ ========================================== REFORMS ==========================================
¬ =============================================================================================

{SMT_A_NEW_MAN__GAIUS_MARIUS_TITLE}	A New Man: Gaius Marius
{SMT_A_NEW_MAN__GAIUS_MARIUS_BODY}	Gaius Marius has proposed a series of laws that allow the proletariat to join his reorganised Roman army. In return for many years of military service every soldier will be given land as a kind of pension. This reform is passed in the people's assembly without the approval of the Senate. It's a certainty that such popular - and populist - appeal will do Marius no favours in the long run!\n\nThe troop types available for recruitment now reflect the structure of this new professional army. Check the recruitment scroll to view the details.

{roman_empire_unstable_currency}	Currency Crisis!
{roman_empire_unstable_currency_body}	The policies of debasement and inflation pursued by previous emperors have undermined all trust in our currency, and it is no longer favoured as a medium of exchange. Some have even reverted to bartering, so low is trust in Roman coin!\n\nUntil we can restore faith in our coin, you will be unable to recruit Merchants to trade in foreign lands.
{roman_empire_stable_currency}	Currency Crisis Resolved
{roman_empire_stable_currency_body}	Our recent investments in mining has worked wonders; we now have the resources to produce coins of high intrinsic worth, and faith in Roman coin is restoring across the world!\n\nYou can now recruit Merchants in settlements with a Market or better.

{SMT_CAMILLAN_REFORMS_TITLE}	Camillan Reforms
{SMT_CAMILLAN_REFORMS_BODY}	Reformed army. Hastati, Principes, Triarii organized by wealth. Hastati, Principes use spears. Triarii are a phalanx. Accensi, Leves, Rorarii are reserved skirmishers.

{SMT_MANIPULAR_REFORMS_TITLE}	Manipular Reforms
{SMT_MANIPULAR_REFORMS_BODY}	Manipular army. Hastati, Principes, now fight as maniples instead of phalanxes.

{SMT_POLYBIAN_REFORMS_TITLE}	New Roman Armaments
{SMT_POLYBIAN_REFORMS_BODY}	The Roman army has undergone many changes in the last few decades. Once again, given the threat posed by Carthage, Rome has seen it fit to revise the armaments and standards of the Roman legion. Inspired by the Iberian mercenaries employed by Carthage, hastati and principes now use a gladius as their primary weapon, and now carry two pila (javelins) to throw before engaging in melee. The triarii have finally abandoned the outdated phalanx formation, swapping out their clipei (round shields) for scuta (rectangular shields).\n\nAlong with these changes, the different ranks are now organized by age and experience, rather than wealth alone. The poorest classes, the accensi, leves, and rorarii, have all been reorganized into a single unit; the Velites (historically, the experience and velite changes were already occuring since the Samnite Wars in 290 BC).\n\nThe troop types available for recruitment now reflect these changes. Check the recruitment scroll to view the details.

{SMT_ANTIGONID_REFORMS_TITLE}	Antigonid Reforms
{SMT_ANTIGONID_REFORMS_BODY}	Alexander units become vanilla Macedon units.

¬ =============================================================================================
¬ ========================================= MESSAGES ==========================================
¬ =============================================================================================

{MESSAGE_ROMAN_MECHANICS}	Roman Mechanics
{MESSAGE_ROMAN_MECHANICS_BODY}	GOVERNMENT BUILDINGS\n\n
WARNING\n\n
Do NOT set settlements to automanage if a Praefectura is buildable. If AI constructs it, you will have to rebuild your previous government.\n\n
The Roman factions have a unique administrative hierarchy, and new government buildings to go along with it. This building tree allows for multiple branching paths, allowing the recruitment of different troops. The Roman municipal hierarchy generally goes as follows:\n\n
Civitas -> Municipium -> Colonia.\n\n
From Civitas Stipendiaria, you can choose to either go the allied route (with regional allies recruitable at Civitas Foederata), or the annexation route (starting at Municipium). Regular Roman units can only be recruited out of Municipia and above.\n\n
Colonias can either be established outright or upgraded to from Municipia, and this is to simulate early Rome establishing colony cities in strategic locations, and later Rome awarding Colonia status to cities as a sign of prestige.\n\n
Praefecturae are a public-order management building and can be built after taking a new city. Every government type except Colonias can be downgraded to a Praefectura if public order becomes too much of a problem.\n\n
Currently, the only regions with allied units are barbarian regions, Greek areas, and Italy. Iberia, North Africa, and eastern areas have yet to be done.\n\n
POLYBIAN REFORMS\n\n
In addition to the government mechanics, a new reform has been introduced for the Romans: the Polybian Reforms. You may have noticed the lack of Velites and your Hastati, Principes, and Triarii are a little different.\n\n
This is to reflect a transitional period from the Camillan system (where Roman units were organized solely by wealth, Velites hadn't been created yet) to the Polybian system, introduced in the time of the Samnite Wars. The purpose of the Polybian "Reforms" in this mod mark the end of this transition.\n\n
The Polybian reforms are required to happen before the Marian reforms. In order to trigger them, you or any other Roman faction need to have captured a total of 12 settlements in Sicily, Sardinia, and/or Corsica (this may be changed if it turns out this is too railroaded).\n\n
If the player is not a Roman faction, the AI just has to have 4 settlements in Italy be at city-level or higher.\n\n
MARIAN REFORMS\n\n
The Marian reforms require the Polybian reforms to happen first. Besides that, it's the same same as vanilla. One huge city in Italy or Sicily, except Rome itself.\n\n
SPECIAL EDICTS\n\n
The Roman factions have access to special edicts, only buildable in their capital; Triumph and Appease the Senate.\n\n
Triumphs can only be built after one or more of the following events occur: a general wins a heroic battle, captures a world wonder, destroys a faction, or gets a Pontifex Maximus seat in the senate. Note that it MUST be a general (i.e, a named character) that does the deed to merit a triumph, not a captain.\n\n
Appease the Senate gives the Senate Gratitude reward, increasing your standing in the Senate.

{MESSAGE_GREEK_MECHANICS}	Government Mechanics
{MESSAGE_GREEK_MECHANICS_BODY}	GOVERNMENT BUILDINGS\n\n
There is a new tree of buildings available to all factions (besides the Romans), which is meant to simulate a faction's cultural influence or control over a region, with building upgrades requiring a certain percentage of the population to be your culture.\n\n
MILITARY\n\n
Military governments give public order bonuses at the cost of growth and taxation. These buildings can be built immediately following a region's conquest, not requiring any percentage of the faction's culture.\n\n
These buildings have two tiers; Occupation, and Martial Law. Military governments can be upgraded to Colonial, Direct, or Aligned government types depending on the conditions.\n\n
COLONIAL\n\n
Colonial governments give public order, growth, and cultural conversion bonuses at the cost of taxation. If a region's native culture does not match the conquesting faction's culture, this building path will be required following a military government.\n\n
These buildings have two tiers; Early and Developed. Colonial governments can be upgraded to the Direct government type once the faction's culture presence has reached a certain threshold.\n\n
DIRECT\n\n
Direct governments buildings give public order and cultural conversion bonuses, with a tax malus or bonus depending on tier.\n\n
These buildings have two tiers; Integrated and Core, with Core being the highest attainable government possible in the system.\n\n
INDIRECT\n\n
Indirect governments give different bonuses and maluses depending on their type. They can be built after a military government's establishment, no faction cultural presence required.\n\n
Tributary states give tax bonuses at the cost of public order.\n\n
Allied states give morale bonuses and public order bonuses\n\n
Free states give trade and public order bonuses.\n\n
NOTICE\n\n
Some factions have different names for the buildings, but the system is the same. The only faction group with a unique government system are the Roman factions.

{MESSAGE_CULTURE_MECHANICS}	Other Mechanics
{MESSAGE_CULTURE_MECHANICS_BODY}	CULTURE SYSTEM\n\n
This mod has a culture system, a repurposing the game's religion system, meant to add more depth to the campaign. Each region on the map has a native culture, which is reflected as a passive cultural conversion rate given by the settlement's core building.\n\n
This cultural conversion can be counteracted by constructing temples, or other culture-promoting buildings, upgrading your local government (different from the governor's residence, more on that later), or moving characters of the desired culture into the settlement.\n\n
In addition, occupying, enslaving, or exterminating settlements replaces a portion of the captured settlement's culture with your own. How much gets replaced depending on the severity of the action.\n\n
WARNING\n\n
If you are having public order problems in your cities due to the regional culture system (especially for colonies), build a temple to make your dominant culture the official culture!\n\n
FACTION SIZE\n\n
The mod also has a faction size mechanic, which gives tax and growth bonuses or debuffs depending on the faction's size. This system is intended to give smaller factions a fighting chance, and to nerf extremely powerful factions like the Seleucids and Mauryas.\n\n
EDICTS\n\n
The mod introduces an edict mechanic, buildings that offer temporary bonuses and expire after a few turns. There are several different edicts offering different bonuses and maluses.\n\n
Edicts can only be built under Direct governments, not Allied.\n\n
ACCREDITATION\n\n
These systems were inspired by systems and scripts from RTR: Imperium Surrectum, with a few things being taken directly from the mod itself. I want to give a huge thanks to the RTR:IS team for their hard work and dedication, and for having their project be open source.

{MESSAGE_SIZE_MECHANICS}	Faction Size Mechanics
{MESSAGE_SIZE_MECHANICS_BODY}	FACTION SIZE MECHANICS\n\n
This mod has a faction size mechanic, which is gives tax and growth bonuses or maluses depending on the faction's size.\n\n
This system is intended to give smaller factions a fighting chance, and to nerf extremely powerful factions like the Seleucids.


¬ =============================================================================================
¬ ============================== EMPIRE SIZE MECHANIC (from RIS) ==============================
¬ =============================================================================================

¬ ============================
¬ size1

{RIS_SIZE1_ENABLE}City State
{RIS_SIZE1_ENABLE_BODY}Empire size one: 1 city

{RIS_SIZE1_DISABLE}No Longer a City-State
{RIS_SIZE1_DISABLE_BODY}We are no longer empire size one: 1 city

¬ ============================
¬ size2

{RIS_SIZE2_ENABLE}Rising Power
{RIS_SIZE2_ENABLE_BODY}We are now empire size two: 2–4 cities

{RIS_SIZE2_DISABLE}No Longer a Rising Power
{RIS_SIZE2_DISABLE_BODY}We are no longer empire size two: 2–4 cities

¬ ============================
¬ size3

{RIS_SIZE3_ENABLE}Minor Power
{RIS_SIZE3_ENABLE_BODY}We are now empire size three: 5–8 cities

{RIS_SIZE3_DISABLE}No Longer a Minor Power
{RIS_SIZE3_DISABLE_BODY}We are no longer empire size three: 5–8 cities

¬ ============================
¬ size4

{RIS_SIZE4_ENABLE}Regional Power
{RIS_SIZE4_ENABLE_BODY}We are now empire size four: 9–15 cities

{RIS_SIZE4_DISABLE}No Longer a Regional Power
{RIS_SIZE4_DISABLE_BODY}We are no longer empire size four: 9–15 cities

¬ ============================
¬ size5

{RIS_SIZE5_ENABLE}Large Power
{RIS_SIZE5_ENABLE_BODY}We are now empire size five: 16–30 cities

{RIS_SIZE5_DISABLE}No Longer a Major Power
{RIS_SIZE5_DISABLE_BODY}We are no longer empire size five: 16–30 cities

¬ ============================
¬ size6

{RIS_SIZE6_ENABLE}Major Power
{RIS_SIZE6_ENABLE_BODY}We are now empire size six: 31–50 cities

{RIS_SIZE6_DISABLE}No Longer a Dominant Power
{RIS_SIZE6_DISABLE_BODY}We are no longer empire size six: 31–50 cities

¬ ============================
¬ size7

{RIS_SIZE7_ENABLE}Rising Empire
{RIS_SIZE7_ENABLE_BODY}We are now empire size seven: 51–100 cities

{RIS_SIZE7_DISABLE}No Longer a Hegemonic Empire
{RIS_SIZE7_DISABLE_BODY}We are no longer empire size seven: 51–100 cities

¬ ============================
¬ size8

{RIS_SIZE8_ENABLE}Empire
{RIS_SIZE8_ENABLE_BODY}We are now empire size eight: 101–200 cities

{RIS_SIZE8_DISABLE}No Longer an Imperial Power
{RIS_SIZE8_DISABLE_BODY}We are no longer empire size eight: 101–200 cities

¬ ============================
¬ size9

{RIS_SIZE9_ENABLE}Large Empire
{RIS_SIZE9_ENABLE_BODY}We are now empire size nine: 201–400 cities

{RIS_SIZE9_DISABLE}No Longer an Imperial Hegemon
{RIS_SIZE9_DISABLE_BODY}We are no longer empire size nine: 201–400 cities

¬ ============================
¬ size10

{RIS_SIZE10_ENABLE}Global Empire
{RIS_SIZE10_ENABLE_BODY}We are now empire size ten: 401+ cities

{RIS_SIZE10_DISABLE}No Longer a Global Empire
{RIS_SIZE10_DISABLE_BODY}We are no longer empire size ten: 401+ cities
